hello
this is active inference textbook group
cohort 2
we're in meeting 10 on November 4th 22.
and we're having our first discussion on
chapter five message passing and
neurobiology
so to begin
does anyone want to share
any general thoughts or remarks
on chapter five just
any experiences they had reading it
any topics that they thought they want
to discuss a little bit today just
anything about their reading of chapter
five
yes Ali
well I think in chapter five uh since
the authors decided to go uh pretty deep
into
neuroanatomical
structures or neuroanatomical uh
substrates of most of the active
inference Concepts uh well
having a kind of basic understanding of
neural neuroanatomy uh in my view is an
essential prerequisite to understanding
the contents of this chapter
uh but otherwise it provides some
empirical evidence for why active
inference modeling Works uh or
to put it this way it explains uh the
some of the testable
predictions we can get from applying uh
from seeing active inference from a
neuroanatomical perspective
awesome
thank you
anyone else want to share a general
thought on chapter five
yeah as Ali stated that chapter is going
to provide a host of examples which are
going to be discussed separately and
then synthesized together
regarding neurobiology specifically
mammalian neurobiology
which is one of the most important
systems of interest of us as humans and
also it's one of the most studied
in terms of different
um zones where active inference models
have been applied ranging from
as we'll see in this chapter the micro
circuit level
so the connectivity patterns of small
numbers of computational elements which
might be like neurons or it could be
brain regions
then there's a discussion of motor
commands
in terms of continuous time active
inference
and how motor
uh behaviors in the periphery are
coordinated
there are then several discussions about
decision making
neuromodulation and learning
and then there's a hierarchical hybrid
model that's presented which integrates
The Continuous and the discrete cases of
active inference in a unified generative
model and that's what brings it all
together in the summary
and also just one note maybe we've
mentioned before
um
chapter one provides an overview of the
book much like chapter 10.
chapter 2 and 3 are the roads to active
inference but not active inference
itself
though it also kind of is
chapter 4 we learned about the essence
of specifying an active inference entity
which is its definition in terms of a
generative model
and now immediately we're moving to the
area with the most empirical support
and popular interest which is
understanding active inference in the
context of mammalian neuroanatomy and
that will conclude the first half of the
book which is the epistemic component
the second half of the book chapter six
through ten heads into some of the
step by step and recipes around
designing active inference models but in
some ways as we complete this last
chapter in the first half of our cohort
it's just good to keep in mind that like
we spent 60 percent of the time
getting into the game
then where the low and the high road
intersected was in the generative model
and now we're immediately going to be
talking about topics related to
applications
and specific generative models applied
to neurobiological phenomena in health
and in disease
okay
does anyone else want to add a comment
on chapter 5 before we start
moving through it
all right
chapter 4 described the generative model
in this chapter there's a focus on the
process theories arising from those
Dynamics theories that explain how the
brain May Implement variational
inference
so as per classical scientific Criterion
the goal of a theory or a contribution
is to variously explain predict design
control
these are the criteria that active
inference can and should be compared and
juxtaposed with other competing theories
and so many of these aspects are going
to be touched upon
explain and predict
and ultimately to design and control but
initially in this setting to explain and
predict so we'll be keeping an eye out
for unique and valuable explanations and
predictions
that active inference modeling of a
given system of Interest provides
in comparison with some other approach
that could be taken
let us take a step back from the
technical material of chapter four The
generative model
and turn our attention to the process
theories accompanying active inference
it's important to draw a distinction
between a principle like the free energy
principle
and a process theory about how the
principle may be implemented in a
certain kind of system such as the brain
the latter lets us develop hypotheses
that are answerable to empirical data so
quite commonly we hear about the
non-falsification or the
non-falcifability of the free energy
principle
as a principal akin to a principle of
least action
and one can see
that
comment addressed at the beginning of
this chapter which is sure whatever you
think about whether free energy
principle is tautological or it can it
can't be falsified
when we develop specific hypotheses
embodied as models of given systems of
Interest then we're certainly in the
space of being able to find unique
explanations and predictions to falsify
or not like we could have one model that
says that two brain regions are
connected in some way and then there
could be an experimental study that
falsifies or adds or removes evidence
to support that claim so this is where
we actually get into the last mile of
scientific modeling
where we're going to be saying specific
things about specific
systems
um
the Dual aim of this chapter is to
introduce readers with a technical
background to the neurobiology of active
inference so that's people coming from a
math
and modeling perspective to learn about
some of the importance neurobiological
substrates
where active inference models have been
constructed over the last 10 or so years
and to highlight to biologists the
relevance of theory to practical
neuroscience
so for those who are coming from more of
uh embodied or biological angle here
why does it matter that we're adding
this mathematical layer on top of the
raw anatomical observations like the
structural connectivity of different
brain regions
is an empirical measurement about the
world
so what are we doing that goes beyond
saying
this is connected to that
and the chapter is not the final word
it is simply some interpretations that
seem most consistent with the currently
available evidence
here they describe how in the following
sections
they're going to uh bring up first as
mentioned briefly before
the role of the micro circuit as a
computational component
which is very common to computational
neuroscience
then moving through motor and cortical
regions of the mammalian neuroscience
to understand first modularly and then
in composition how decisions around
motor behaviors can be seen as the
coordination among multiple active
inference generative models
anyone want to give a general thought or
just like something that's interesting
or exciting about
this framing
okay
section 5.2 micro circuits and messages
so in chapter four there was a
discussion about belief updating which
we spoke a little bit about in terms of
message passing and belief propagation
in Bayesian graphical Networks
and here they provide some written
overview
of the layered structure of the
mammalian cortex so does anyone want to
give a note on the mammalian cortex or
the layer structure the so-called
six-layer structure of the mammalian
cortex
so just for context this is like
um let's see where where it's actually
sliced through
here we have a prototypical mammalian
brain I'm always emphasizing mammalian
because this is not some general
um property of brains like invertebrate
brains have a very different layout they
don't have cortical layers in the same
way
um and so these cortical regions
near the top of the head
if one slices through them
they reveal a very specific pattern of
cells
that are arranged in these laminar or
layer like ways
and so there are these
um
six
areas
six layers one two three four five
um
maybe that should be six
um or maybe there's some other thing
happening here but this is representing
like a slice
through cortex
and so this has been modeled as a column
because as you go across
the cortical surface
there are these repeating units that
have this kind of laminar structure
it's like six layers of Locker
across the cortical surface
once it's unfolded and then sliced
through
and that's represented
from a
Bayesian computational
view in figure 5.1
canonical cortical microcircuits
illustrating relationship between
inferential message passing and the
architecture of the cerebral cortex
on the left
is a schematic of some Anatomy
where the different connections
represent
inhibitory or excitatory
synapses
so in high inhibitory synapses
reduce the likelihood of the downstream
neuron firing when activated and up and
excitatory synapses increase the
likelihood of the downstream neuron
firing when activated so the left is not
a base graph it's actually a summary of
structural
anatomical histological that means
tissue level Anatomy connectivity
in the middle
is a message passing architecture
so like a scheme for variables and their
connectivity within a hierarchical
predictive processing architecture
and on the right side is a message
passing scheme that's described to solve
a partially observable Markov decision
process pomdp
now on the left is an empirical
neuroanatomical
structural map
on the right we see two computational
implementations of inference and action
and they're being kind of laid out they
could be laid out in any way they could
look like um the Big Dipper
graphically
but they're being
juxtaposed with the cortical layers
so that we can start to see some
concordances
and resonances between the location of a
given variable
in a statistical model of inference and
action and the neurobiological
substrates
who with plausible biological
connectivity
might be implementing or doing something
like the computational role that the
variables play
in the abstract models
so that's going to be the path towards
or the template of the path towards
unique explanations and predictions
from using computational modeling of the
structural neural Anatomy
does anyone have any thoughts or
questions on
um figure five one or like
how a structural anatomical empirical
map
might be juxtaposed with
statistical models
um maybe a good thing to think about our
question answer here is like
what connections or what
um
structure
reflects something like a a belief in
the statistical sense
um
or what connection could be made there
so what
neurobiological structures can reflect
or represent beliefs
sure yeah
that's fair
when what way are they different or yeah
what what's not a belief here
does anyone have any a lot of arrows
thoughts yeah
and the quarterback
he's gonna sit here
yeah
one thing I notice immediately in this
uh previously is just the cortical
layers there and the there's this two on
the
right hand side of that for layer three
and layer four so I'm not sure what
exactly
yeah yes oh okay yep yep
um one important thing to note
about the cortical layers which is
almost
um
obtrusively under discussed
is the cortical column performs as one
integrated unit
the fact that it's six layers doesn't
mean that there's like a little octave
Loop and then a second active Loop and
then a third active Loop so it's not
like a six if someone said I'm looking
at a six layer predictive processing
hierarchy
one might think that there's like six
cleanly separated layers of a wedding
cake
but actually the cortical column has six
arbitrarily defined
not to say that there's no grounding but
there's finer scale differences and
there's coursing and there's overlapping
zones
and it's behaving with connections that
span across multiple layers
so this isn't like a clean six layer
predictive processing model
this is like one integrated architecture
that functions with this connectivity
and importantly this is the basis of
like the Thousand brains hypothesis and
numenta Ai and people who have been
pursuing the cortical architecture as
the or a basis for intelligence in
natural and artificial systems
and it's long been hypothesized when
comparing the brains of different
mammals like what neuroanatomical
features are associated with differences
in perceived intelligence or learning
capacity
and one of the features is the
prevalence in the primates and in humans
of higher cortical regions so-called
higher cortical regions with this
specific architecture
whereas other brain regions maybe have
not
had so much evolution in their
um size
or in their circuitry
that doesn't mean that they're
unimplicated in intelligence it just
means that people have looked for where
there are more differences
um
to this question that Brock asked about
like where might beliefs be
embodied
So within the Bayesian setting the
statistical setting
a belief is just any parameterization
can be said to be a belief about a
variable so we're not
talking about experienced or personally
held or verbally stateable beliefs we're
talking about statistical
parameterization of a given variable
and there's at least two ways one can
think about beliefs being represented or
embodied in a structure of this
and we're going through this in slow
time because like this kind of general
questions about what is the structural
neuroanatomy and how does it relate to
statistical modeling thereof
is going to be at the heart of the
following examples
as well not just this cortical
um case
um one can see the firing rate of a
neuron
in like an artificial neural network
setting or just the value that a
statistical variable takes on
as representing a belief about that
variable
then one can think about the presence or
absence or the waiting or the type like
inhibitory excitatory of a connection
between two variables
as embodying
a hypothesis about
the structure of how those variables are
connected
under the implicit assumption that we're
developing models that actually do
functional things
of course one could just connect all of
the variables and have an all by all
model
however as we sparsify the relationships
amongst variables which is to say remove
edges from the all by all
the model becomes computationally easier
to fit
and we talk about that in terms of the
factorizability
of the variational Bayesian approach
so if none of the variables were
connected they're all independently fit
that's like the simplest it can be
to fit n variables
if all the variables were interacting in
combinatoric ways
that would be increasingly
computationally complex and for a given
amount of data we would have less and
less statistical power to resolve any
given variable or combination of
variables because the same amount of
information from our observations
is now being like partitioned and spread
out over
fitting estimates for more and more
variables
and so
what biological systems do and what
statistical models do
is enforce either just through physical
constraints or through
design
sparsity conditions
on functional statistical modules
such that the models are more computable
though they only may be exploring a
subset of the space of total possible
models
exploring well
a subset
whose sparsity embodies certain aspects
of the world
maybe a more appropriate
um model to fit situationally
figure 5.2
simplified version of the predictive
coding scheme shown in the middle of
five one
so does anyone want to give a thought on
5-2
foreign
so here's message passing between three
cortical regions so here's three
cortical columns each consisting of like
one through six layers
and
um there's going to be message passing
happening laterally
dotted lines show ascending messages
prediction errors and solid lines show
descending messages or predictions
so in this setting
um this rightmost region
is like the quote top most but left
right top down bottom up those are all
just spatial metaphors
but we'll continue to use this higher
and lower in the hierarchical modeling
where the lower levels of the
hierarchical model
are more close to where the rubber hits
the road in terms of like the perceptual
machinery and the action effectors
and higher levels of a hierarchy are
associated with more and more abstract
or general or deeper or slower features
of the world
so
this figure
is representing how
um there is a uh
within cortical column relationship
between predictions
and prediction errors
between a superficial and the Deep
levels
using the concordance between variables
and cortical layers established in 5.1
and then
the um
outcome of one cortical layer
can also be engaged in this prediction
and prediction error relationship
with
an anatomically lateral cortical column
however from a computational perspective
this is like the top the middle and the
bottom
of a three layer cognitive model
the superscripts are describing the
level so here's like I I plus 1 and I
minus 1.
so this is just describing that this is
a scheme that can be
computationally extended to many levels
of hierarchical modeling
and it's being embodied by the lateral
juxtaposition
neuroanatomically of cortical columns
Ali did you have something you wanted to
add there
uh well yeah I I just wanted to
mention friston's uh recent paper from a
couple of months ago uh in which
uh the neurobiological substrate of uh
prediction errors are explained uh in in
detail namely the computational
Psychiatry which is a great
overview paper of
the whole field of computation
Psychiatry through the lens of active
inference and especially
in on the matter of
prediction error I'm sorry a matter of
prediction error I just wanted to uh
point the section uh let me
sorry yeah
You're The Importance of Being precise I
I just wanted to quote a couple of
sentences from this paper which says
and predicting or estimating uh
Precision is a universal requisite for
making sense of data from estimating the
signal to noise ratio in some sensory
apparatus through to estimating standard
error when making inference bison nyman
Pearson statistic affording certain
prediction errors greater Precision
increases their influence on belief
updating and has all the Hallmarks of
attentional selection physiologically
this simply entails an increase in the
excitability or post-synaptic gain of
neuronal populations broadcasting
prediction errors
on this view there is an intimate
relationship between attention and the
modulation of synaptic efficacy by
classical neuromodulators and non-linear
postsynaptic responses responsible for
mediating the exchange between fast
fighting spiking inhibitory interneurons
and superficial pyramidal cells so
it's basically the arguments from the
book but in a much more concise and a
little bit well-structured argument in
my opinion so if anyone wants to
um just look at this paper I think it
might be helpful in grasping uh the
material uh which is I'm posting the
link here in the chat
awesome
yeah thank you for sharing it just to
kind of
again as we walk towards unique
explanations and predictions for active
inference models of
empirical neural Anatomy we can think
about at least a few areas of alignment
between these models so there's
structural alignment where realized
anatomical connections
have
parallels
to statistical Connections in a Bayesian
graph
they are not one and the same but it's
just an area of alignment that can be
used to explore predictions and
explanations
then also there's two areas that are
mentioned by what Ali just read which
are some of the functional components
for example neural firing rates or
um synchronizations and other sorts of
dynamical
functional relationships
like when this variable is high that one
is lower whether they're connected or
not structurally
and chemical features like
neuromodulation or the presence or
absence of an excitatory or inhibitory
neuromodulator at a given synapse or
even
taking us into synaptic plasticity
and the neuromodulation of hebeian
associative learning
all of these areas
when brought together
in a total fabric of evidence
help us strengthen the relationship
between the computational models and the
neural anatomical empirical findings
and then they suggest things to each
other
so that was heavily on the cortical
architecture of the column
and then how laterally linked columns
which again is their empirical
structural connectivity patterns can be
thought of in terms of hierarchical
Bayesian modeling
then they move into motor commands
so
let's think about the layer V of the
cortex
projecting as a projection
so layer V of the column here is this DP
deep criminal cell that's just the name
of the cell it has a certain
architecture that makes it called
perimetable terminal
um this is like classic Santiago
romanica Hall stuff
and um it has this Arrow coming out
going to motor neurons so here's like a
motor output
from this cortical column
not all cortical columns are involved in
motor outputs but some are
so we're going to be receiving
inputs from those pyramidal neurons
and it's going to be projecting onto a
butterfly no this is a cross section of
the neural cord the spinal cord of a
mammal
figure five three
neuroanatomy associated with active
inference in modulating spinal motor
reflexes
coming in to the system from the proprio
sensors
afferent meaning like
um away from the sensor as opposed to
efferent
the proprioceptive afferent signal
is being compared in an error-like
fashion with an Epsilon
with
the descending taught down predictions
coming from that cortical column that we
just looked at
the output of this comparison is
a motor message or command or signal to
a motor actuator
so one can imagine that where
proprioception
exactly matches expectations around
no
motor movement might be passed forward
I'm trying to hold my hand on the table
all signals are suggesting that the
expectation is being realized
and no movement is enacted
in comparison if one expects
to be receiving different proprioceptive
afferent information which is to say to
be in a different postural position
then motor commands can be enacted to
reduce that Divergence
so different proprio receptors for
example are in your elbow
such that there's a different
proprioceptive afferent coming in when
your elbow is extended
and when it's completely closed
and then
expectations
in the head
the brain
can change
such that different motor commands are
enacted to open and or close the elbow
dynamically
as
authentic proprioceptive information
comes in
so broadly that is this neural Anatomy
any thoughts or questions on it
uh actually there's
um I think it was in the beginning of
section
5.3 uh there's a sentence which might uh
result in some uh misunderstanding your
confusions which says the schematic on
the left in figure 5.1 shows that layer
5 of the cortex projects with spinal
pyramidal neurons and that this can be
interpreted as a prediction but if we
look at figure 5.2 I'm sorry 5.1
we we won't see
um
this explicitly
um I mean anything labeled as a spinal
pyramidal neurons because uh
because the primary citation neural cell
types in corticospinal tract is
pyramidal Neuron spinal motor neurons
and spinal parameter neurons are
sometimes used interchangeably so in
this figure actually what we see is an
excited worry connection which is drawn
from layer 5 to spinal motor neurons and
not spinal pyramidal neurons but they're
basically the same things so I just
wanted to clear up that uh
if anyone has that misunderstanding
thank you the pyramidal neuron
there's a large diversity of structure
but
if you like squiggles that look like
this
you'll love cellular neuroscience
all right
um there's an extremely interesting
discussion around sensory attenuation
in the context of motor initiation and
completion
so
we need a way when we want to make a
move so to speak we need a way to
preclude sensory data from updating our
expectations so that we can entertain
the initially false belief that we are
moving so this belief can be realized
through action
so let's just imagine that we're in a
case where we are expecting the elbow to
be closed but the proprioceptive
information is suggesting that it's
extended
if
um you know
the cortical hierarchy simply changes
its belief
to it I believe that it is closed
that will immediately be overwritten by
the vertical proprioceptive information
coming in
and so as we know there's two ways to
update the generative model and to
minimize free energy changing the world
and changing your mind so here it's like
change the body or change the mind
and under high Precision information
coming in
changing one's Minds will be brought
back into alignment with the high
attention which is to say high Precision
to the sensory information coming back
in
and so the computational strategy
implemented
is
that the descending motor tracks predict
not just the data but the Precision or
the confidence placed in those data so
high Precision high confidence High
attention that means you snap to
whatever that is being
uh whatever that high attention high
confidence High attention variable is
saying
in the extreme just whatever it said in
the last time Point becomes your
estimate
the opposite extreme is low confidence
low Precision low attention
and in that case no matter what that
signal says you don't change your mind
at all
and so what happens is
previously we're talking about the
elbows prediction around being like open
or closed but now let's think about it
as providing a
um
uh expectation and a variance
coming down
um so initially the confidence placed in
those data are decreased
that allows movement to be initiated
this is known as sensory attenuation and
can be thought of as the complement to
sensory attention so attenuation just is
low attention
diminishing increasing of attention
equipping us with the capacity to ignore
certain prediction errors such as
generated by psychatic eye movements
where sensory attenuation is known as
psychotic suppression
so other than the blind spot and so on
cycatic suppression is one of the most
interesting examples of kind of embodied
Precision modulation
like when you do an isocade which can
happen multiple times per seconds
there's no nausea or vertigo except when
it's pathological
because
during that motor movement
there's a reduced attention to the
bottom-up visual input and this is
highly highly empirically demonstrated
in multiple areas of the visual
processing neurobiology
so that like when the eye is still
there's an increased attention to the
incoming raw bottom-up information
when the eye is moving there's a
decreased attention to the bottom-up
information and an increased Reliance on
the generative model during those
transients of cicada
and so similarly to initiate a movement
requires an initial suppression of
precision
alongside a change in expected
expectation of proprioception
and that's what allows one to believe
like okay I'm going to get out of the
chair
I believe that I'm out of the chair and
then that shifts the balance of
minimizing free energy towards changing
your body AKA changing the world through
action
rather than immediately just getting
your change your mind
knocked back into place
and interestingly this is absolutely
Concordance
with many healthy neurodiversity and
pathological scenarios
involving
um the neurobiology of failure to
initiate continue or terminate movement
so like there's scenarios where somebody
may have trouble beginning movements but
once they've begun movement they can
walk normally
alternatively there are motor
behaviors where somebody may have
trouble terminating Behavior
and so these can be modeled from a
computational perspective so that not
only are we able to say well this
chemical is higher in this condition or
people with this diagnosis tend to have
this comorbidity
but we can actually think about the
parameterization of these computational
models
and have some more Nuance around well
should we be increasing what or
modulating what Ollie
actually there's an interesting argument
in Mark's home's uh book The Hidden
Spring which says that
because
Consciousness I mean it says that
Consciousness is only required to
mediate mismatches between internal and
external States the more adaptively and
predictively reliable our model becomes
the more our Behavior becomes automated
operating below the level of conscious
experience so basically it says that
Consciousness is needed in situations
where surprisal needs to be minimized
when there's no surprisal there's not
much need for Consciousness or in other
words
Consciousness is a process that somehow
seeks to overcome itself
um
well very deep
thank you for sharing it
okay
just to peer ahead into where we're
going in the second half of five and
then people can think about some
questions hopefully write them down as
they see fit so now we're coming back
into the brain into the subcortical
structures
so beneath the layer of Cortex
that has the histology described by the
columnar architecture are the
subcortical structures sometimes
referred to as being in the midbrain
specifically there's going to be a
discussion of the basal ganglia
and colleagues
this is one of the regions in the brain
that has been implicated through many
neuroimaging and disease related and all
kinds of different studies
in decision making and learning and it's
known to have some dopaminergic
characteristics
expression of signaling related to
dopamine and actually only a very small
fraction of cells in the in the
mammalian or invertebrate neuroanatomy
are dopaminergic in this way
it's not like every neuron is responsive
to to dopamine
um
some of the details are described
some of the mathematical parallels are
drawn and here
it culminates in
a uh indirect pathway and direct pathway
of decision making
that are Which choice between these two
Pathways is favored
is going to be computationally assigned
to the role of this gamma variable
and these two pathways
can be thought of as sort of like
deliberative decision making
in the direct pathway
and instinctual or habitual decision
making in the indirect pathway
how do we see that playing out
observations are coming in
and in both cases policy pie are coming
out
so this neuroanatomy
is implementing a computation that takes
in some type of input from the cerebral
cortex which again might be a prediction
about something else and results in
policy evaluation and selection
e is the variable representing
affordances and it can be thought of as
like a habit Vector because it
characterizes not just what can be done
but the Baseline frequencies or
probabilities of those actions to be
done
whereas G is expected free energy and
that relies not on the past
habits and ratios of performance of
different behaviors
without consideration to the impact of
those behaviors but rather the expected
free energy calculations around
different policies that could be
undertaken
so here we can start to see differences
in decision making
where sometimes this is sort of a type 1
type 2
manifolds in terms of like quick simple
decisions that don't even need to
reference the future
on the indirect pathway and
deliberative potentially planning like
operations involving expected free
energy calculations and a dopaminergic
neuromodulatory feature
that balances the relative contributions
of these two decision-making Pathways
with respect to their influence on
policy
table 5.1
describes neurotransmitters
they're Associated computational role
even though they all play many roles
this is just a coarse draining and a
sort of starting point
and then empirical evidence
around the role of that neurotransmitter
in that computational way
many work by first and at all many work
just in the normal Neuroscience route
5.6
is going to move us towards it's a short
section
um
moving us towards
thinking about stitching and composing
together
hierarchical active inference generative
models that have continuous and discrete
State spaces together
because as they write
our interface in the world around us in
the Contin is in the continuous domain
the implication of which is at the
lowest level of any hierarchy in the
brain must be continuous
however as decision making becomes more
and more abstracted
it can be seen increasingly in certain
cases as symbolic or discrete
so from the perspective of a generative
model that means associating alternative
discrete hypotheses about the world
with continuous Dynamics entailed by
those hypotheses turn left or turn right
bring an umbrella don't bring an
umbrella is it raining or not friend or
enemy
juxtaposed with the continuous
information arising from the body
and in summary
with a short section again
they are now going to link together the
three neuroanatomical systems that are
described in the chapter
under the spirit of this type of
continuous discrete hybrid generative
modeling approach
specifically we see this cortical
hierarchy
that is engaged in a relationship
in with a subcortical structures
a biologically plausible relationship
which reflects the actual structural
anatomical connectivity between cortical
and subcortical structures
and of appropriate computational
parallelisms
#explanations and predictions
and in the brain
the cortical and subcortical
architectures
are ultimately resulting in this study
with outputs that then engage the spinal
column in the reflex arc that was
described earlier
so policies might be discrete throw the
baseball or don't
and that can be using complex cortical
predictive processing like decision
making
facilitated by this dopaminergically
mediated handoff between more
instinctual habitual like behavior and
more deliberative like expected free
energy comparisons
and that can be enacted
through
a prediction minimizing approach
carried out in the spinal column
this is continuous whereas policies can
be discretized
that's a short chapter there's no
equations there's some variables in the
figures but there aren't really
equations
this
chapter
over the years will be fractally
unpacked
to the most incredible level of detail
they are just raising some key points
and pointing some initial steps Ollie
foreign
as I uh mentioned in the previous cohort
I just wanted to recommend this talk uh
from Thomas Parr which summarizes most
of the points in this chapter and some
more uh and uh I highly highly recommend
it for anyone uh reading this chapter
because it really helps understanding
some of the more obscure Concepts here
thank you excellent okay any final
thoughts or we will close this session
okay
thank you cohort too